Contact

954-465-7228 (Mobile) faris.kadir@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/fariskadir-05966691 (LinkedIn) fariskadir.github.io/ Professional_Portfolio/ (Portfolio) github.com/FarisKadir (Other)

Top Skills

Training
Team Building
Healthcare Information Technology

Certifications

Microsoft Project 2016 Essential Training

98-364: MTA: Database Fundamentals

Faris Kadir

Enterprise Solutions Manager at Andor Health Greater Orlando

0.00.0. 0.10.100

Summary

I am passionate about all things Information Technology/Computer Science related, whether it be networking, server management, database administration, or programming. I have a strong desire to learn and gain more experience in all industries that utilize these technologies.

Qualifications:

- 20 years PC Troubleshooting experience.
- 20 years Customer Service experience.
- 7 years HL7 experience.
- 7 years data integration experience.
- 4 years management experience.
- 4 years of Microsoft SQL experience.
- 4 years supporting EHR software.
- 7 year of troubleshooting network related issues.
- Familiar with and have working knowledge of Windows Server 2008 and 2012.
- Working experience with HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, MS SQL and Python
- Familiar with relational database models.
- Familiar with networking technologies and OSI model.
- Familiar with and having working knowledge of Project Management tasks; Project Plans, MS Project Server,
- Knowledgeable of virtualization softwares; VMware Workstation 10 and Oracle Virtual Box.
- Familiar with Epic Foundation, HPF, Cerner Millenium, McKesson, Sorian, and numerous other Healthcare technologies.
- Proficient in MS Excel, Word, Power Point, Access, Project, Outlook, and Visio.

Experience

Andor Health Enterprise Solutions Manager December 2020 - Present (3 months)

Orlando, Florida, United States

CareMessage

Senior Implementation Project Manager March 2018 - December 2020 (2 years 10 months)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

- Reduced project timelines from 9 months to 3 months by streamlining implementation processes.
- Created project plan templates based on different customer types (FQHC, Health Plan, Government Organizations).
- Created and approved SOWs for all new customer implementations.
- Assigned projects to implementation project management team based on current resource bandwidth and complexity of projects.
- Conducted scoping calls with prospective customers to provide implementation recommendations to customers based on their organization initiatives and goals.
- Responsible for numerous internal company initiatives such as:
- Reducing time to go-live for implementations.
- Educating the support team in order to enable them to take on more complex projects/tickets.
- Redesign existing interfaces to work more efficiently and require less maintenance long term.
- Designing new integrations between various EMR and Population Health systems (Epic and Azara) and CareMessage platform to utilize all features of the platform.
- Assist in designing new API interfaces for CareMessage platform.
- Evaluating cost to serve customers.
- Evaluating time to serve customers.
- Creating documentation for all integration builds.
- Onboard newly hired implementation project managers.
- Create project plans for implementation projects using SmartSheets.
- Act as project manager for implementation projects; conducting weekly status meetings, coordinating between various teams, and evaluating risks and issues that arise during the course of the implementation project.
- Train customers on how to use CareMessage proprietary healthcare text messaging platform.

• Develop process for customers to utilize CareMessage platform with minimal changes to their existing workflow.

Envision Physician Services
HL7 Business Analyst Team Lead - Consultant
May 2017 - March 2018 (11 months)
Plantation. FL

- Gather business requirements for Billing and Quality data for Radiology, Neonatology, Anesthesia, and Emergency Medicine lines of business.
- Design integration build, HL7 and non-HL7, based on requirements.
- Create functional requirements for each build.
- Create Integrated Testing scripts for each build.
- Collaborate with Dev and QA teams to address issues and establish solutions with each build.
- Identify possible roadblocks and solutions with integration and present to business stakeholders.
- Coordinate with Network Ops and Firewall/VPN teams to establish connectivity with vendors.
- Provide production support for existing HL7 interfaces in production environments.
- Analyze various HL7 message types and non-HL7 flat file reports to validate data elements needed for business rules are present.
- Establish any custom development logic/rules that may be needed to accommodate business requirements.
- Review all bugs discovered by QA and present solutions.
- Collaborate with colleagues for process improvement.
- Create various templates to be used for process standardization.
- Educate junior analysts on techniques to analyze data and assist with all the above responsibilities.

MEDNAX, Health Solutions Partner HL7 Interface Analyst II August 2015 - May 2017 (1 year 10 months) Sunrise, FL

- Elicit business requirements for large scale HL7 integrations.
- Translate and simplify business requirements.
- Design HL7 integration build based on requirements.
- Create use cases to support requirements and intended functionality.
- Document functional specifications.
- Design rules engine logic to be used for application builds.

- Perform functional, map record, and integrated testing for custom HL7 interfaces
- Establish scope and timelines for new integration projects.
- Manage project tasks and assure timelines are being met.
- Coordinate with Network Infrastructure, QA, DBA and Development teams to assure successful build and implementation of HL7 interfaces.
- Create UAT test scripts.
- Conduct UAT testing on various HL7 interface builds as well as various outbound documentation feeds.
- Provide level 3 support for existing HL7 interfaces in production environments.
- Conduct end user training on proprietary EMR software.
- Participate in establishing process improvement strategies.
- Create troubleshooting and instructional documentation for support teams and end users.
- Train new employees to complete the above listed responsibilities.
- Educate junior employees on how to use Mirth Connect Interface engine.
- Maintain and re-test existing HL7 interfaces based on vendor requirements, ie for EMR or Interface Engine upgrades.

Qnomy, Inc Implementation Specialist March 2015 - August 2015 (6 months) Miami, FL

- Provide support for clients via phone, email and on-site if needed for proprietary Queue management / Appointment scheduling web application, Q-Flow. After hours support also provided to assure clients had no issues with application.
- Provide on-site installation of software/hardware for client sites. Nationwide travel involved.
- Provide on-site and remote training of application software for users.
- Create training manuals and user guides.
- Troubleshoot application issues on Web and Database servers.
- Perform application demonstrations for potential clients.
- Attend and demo application at industry tradeshows and conferences. Most recently Patient Flow Summit for healthcare industry.
- Assist Project Managers with BRD, SRD, and overall planning and configuration of implementing web application.
- Troubleshooting IIS and MS SQL Server 2008/2012.
- Establish remote connections to client servers via GoToAssist, RDC, VPN.

- Review system logs, such as event viewer and application logs, to identify and resolve problems and errors.
- Utilize third party software to assist in monitoring and troubleshooting application, workstations, servers, and network issues.
- Constantly coming up with ways to make the application work more efficiently given client specific server configurations.
- Planning and implementing server migrations of web application and database.
- Provide maintenance on client servers.
- Recommend additional features/functionality based on client needs.

gMed

Tier II Technical Application Support Analyst August 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 8 months) Weston, FL

- Provide support for Tier 1 and Tier 2 issues with clients via phone and email.
- Collaborate with product development team to identify and resolve software bugs by applying hot fixes and patches.
- Establish remote connections to client servers via rdp, logmein, join.me, showmypc, vpn, and team viewer to troubleshoot problems.
- Utilize third party software to assist in monitoring and troubleshooting application, workstations, servers, and network issues.
- Troubleshoot and resolve all issues that affect proprietary software including; servers, workstations, network and workflow issues.
- Run SQL queries on database to further research cases, update information in database, and apply hotfixes. Basic statements such as SELECT, JOIN, DELETE, UPDATE.
- Analyzed HL7 messages and interfaces that were configured with EHR, lab vendors, and client's practice management system to resolve any malfunctions.
- Troubleshoot issues with Mirth interface engine.
- Install and configure Ubuntu w/ Hylafax for client servers. Also configured fax modem ports via command line using putty.exe to remote into the Ubuntu server.
- Troubleshoot faxing issues using Hylafax Webmin Module.
- Updated and configure custom interfaces to accommodate changes made on clients systems and on interfaces from third party vendors.
- Identified re-occurring issues on client systems and find permanent resolutions.

- Assisted clients in setting up new vital sign monitors to work with EHR.
- Assisted clients with configuring document scanners, document printers, and label printers to work within EHR application.
- Educate clients on how to use the application to best fit their workflow.
- Collaborate with team members to identify issues caused by upgrades to newer versions of application.
- Train new and existing team members on troubleshooting techniques and applying hotfixes.
- Effectively manage workload to assure all deadlines were being met and SLA goals were achieved.

Self Employed PC Technician (Freelance) 2000 - 2014 (14 years) Broward/Miami-Dade County

- Diagnose PC Hardware and software issues via remote or house calls.
- Virus/Malware Removal.
- PC Optimization.
- · Hardware installation.
- · Custom Built PCs.
- OS Installation/Upgrade.
- Configuring wireless network.
- Configuring network printing and sharing.
- Identify and resolve home networking issues.
- Software installs and training, such as MS Office.

Global Response Assistant Manager 2011 - 2013 (2 years)

Margate, Fl

- Manage 50+ employees daily.
- Quality audit. Verifying all work that was assigned to employees was completed to acceptable standards by deadlines.
- Created and updated training manuals on a monthly basis.
- Trained all employees on rules, regulations, company policies and standards, and workflow procedures.
- Interacted with clients on a one on one basis daily to address any issues and concerns with work performance and to adjust workflow of employees if needed.

- Collaborated with fellow management to develop new strategies to manage the department and allow the department to run more effectively.
- Coordinated assignments for teams using Gantt charts to verify tasks were completed in the timeframe expected.
- Supervising and coaching employees to re-enforce rules of conduct and good work standards.

Alliance Entertainment Customer Service Representative 2006 - 2009 (3 years)

Coral Springs, Fl

- Logged each incoming call and email in CRM software.
- Interacted with clients daily to address any issues with orders.
- Authorized returns/refunds for clients.
- Credited customers for discrepancies in pricing of product, such as overpricing.
- Coordinated store visits with clients and field teams to assure product displays were up to company standards.
- Filed and organized paperwork for client claims, refunds, and credits.

Education

Broward College

Bachelor's Degree, Information Technology (2013 - 2015)

Broward College

Associate's Degree, Biology, General · (2011 - 2013)